Inventory of the Addition to the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1919-1980
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Addition to the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1919-1980
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 84-8e
The collection consists of 2 boxes, 30 oversize items and 85 photographs.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the Hardy Cross Dillard papers was given to the library in late 1991 by his widow, Valgerdur Dillard.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Hardy Cross Dillard papers was given to the library in late 1991 by his widow, Valgerdur Dillard. Of interest in the files are congratulatory letters Dillard received when he was appointed dean of the University of Virginia School of Law. In addition there are numerous awards, certificates and degrees Dillard received throughout his life, as well as photographs dating from 1911 to 1980.
Contents List
- Correspondence and Memorabilia
  - Congratulatory Letters: University of Virginia Deanship Appointment, A-J 1963, 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Congratulatory Letters: University of Virginia Deanship Appointment, K-Y 1963, 2 folders (Box 90)
  - Congratulatory Letters: World Court Appointment, A-Y 1969, 5 folders (Box 90)
  - Mid-term grades, University of Virginia 1919 (Box 90)
  - Footnotes for "The Principle of Estoppel" written by HCD in Paris 1931 (Box 90)
  - CASALOG: newsletter for the Civil Affairs Staging Area, Presidio, Monterey, CA [during the time HCD was Commanding Officer] 1945 (Box 90)
  - Midwinters, The Virginia Spectator with article about HCD 1957 (Box 90)
  - Alumni News of Virginia Episcopal School with article about HCD and group picture on cover (HCD 4 rows back mid-center) 1971 January-March (Box 90)
- Awards, Certificates, and Degrees: Oversize
  - Degrees
    - Bachelor of Science, United States Military Academy 1924
    - Doctor of Laws, Tulane University 1971
    - Doctor of Laws, Washington College 1978
  - University of Virginia Awards, Recognition, etc.:
    - Beta Theta Pi membership 1919
    - The Raven Society 1926
    - Virginia Law Review, Decisions Editor 1926-1927
    - Thomas Jefferson Award 1967
    - Legal Research Group 1968
    - Sesquicentennial Award 1969
    - English-Speaking Union 1970
    - Thomas Jefferson Society of Alumni 1977
  - Military Certificates, Commendations, etc.:
    - School of Military Government, Graduate 1942
    - School of Military Government, Instructor 1943
    - United States Army, Reserve Commissioned Officer 1953
    - Army War College, Consultant and Advisor 1956
    - Unites States Army, Retired Reserve 1962
    - United States Air Force, Special Advisory Committee on the Air Force Academy 1965
    - United States Air Force, Exceptional Service Award 1970
    - Judge Advocate General's School, Guest Instructor 1971
  - Miscellaneous Awards or other recognitions:
    - The Academy of International Law at the Pontifica Bolivariana, Corresponding Member 1946
    - Virginia State Bar, Certificate of Appreciation 1959
    - American Bar Foundation, Fellow 1966
    - Washington and Lee University, Recognition 1968
    - The Practical Lawyer, CLE contribution 1969
    - World Association of Judges, Membership 1970
    - Society of the Cincinnati, Member 1972
    - Washington College School of Law, American University, Mooers Lecturer 1977
    - Cum Laude Society, Virginia Episcopal Chapter 1977
    - American Bar Foundation, Honorary Member of Fellows n.d.
  - Other:
    - United States Court of Appeals, Fourth Circuit, Admission to the Bar 1960
- Photographs
  - Alumni Association of leaders n.d.
  - Class of 1927 at 50th reunion 1977 May
  - HCD with siblings [ca. 1970?]
  - HCD with teachers and classmates n Paris 1911-12
  - HCD with Virginia Episcopal School baseball and football teams 1918, n.d.
  - HCD in West Point uniform [ca. 1920]
  - HCD with IMP members 1925-26
  - HCD with unidentified group of students 1926-27
  - HCD (formal pose) [late 1920's?]
  - HCD with group at National War College [?] [late 1940's?]
  - Photos taken at the Civil Affairs Staging Area (CASA), Presidio of Monterey, California--61 photos taken from a scrapbook 1944-45, 7 loose
  - HCD with four others, Shanghai, China 1945
  - HCD with Judge Thomas Michie and Colonel Robert Stumpf upon Dillard's retirement from reserve duty in the U.S. Army 1962
  - HCD with other members of the Special Advisory Committee on the Air Force Academy 1965
  - HCD receiving a special citation for outstanding service to the United States Air Force 1965
  - HCD receiving the Air Force's Decoration for Exceptional Service, 1946-1970 1970
  - HCD with Armistead Boothe and William Battle at Banquet for Emerson Spies 1980
  - HCD on a camel in Egypt with [Morris Leibman?] n.d.